Guide to the Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University, Student Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University, student records
1906-1965
RU 709
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
238.2
The records consist of student files and dean's files documenting academic performance of students in the Yale Sheffield Scientific School.
Yale University. Sheffield Scientific School
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 31-F (YRG 31-F), Student records of the Sheffield Scientific School.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of student files and dean's files documenting academic performance of students in the Yale Sheffield Scientific School.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
College students; Science students; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Sheffield Scientific School
- Student records for the classes of 1921-1955, 1917-1955; Accession 19ND-A-412 (Box 1–88)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2035
  Scope and Contents
  No online inventory available. Paper inventory available in repository.
- Student records for the classes of 1918-1963, 1914-1963; Accession 1973-A-011 (Box 1–44)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2039
- Student records for the Classes of 1906-1941, 1902-1941; Accession 2001-A-066
  Open for research.
  - Class of 1906 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1907 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1908
    - Abbe-Sears (Box 2)
    - Shailor-Z (Box 3)
  - Class of 1909
    - A-Preston (Box 3)
    - Prosser-Lee (Box 4)
  - Class of 1910
    - Aldrich-Peck (Box 5)
    - Perkins-Zimmerman (Box 6)
  - Class of 1911
    - Achilles-Hillhouse (Box 6)
    - Hitt-Zimowski (Box 7)
  - Class of 1912
    - Adams-Bomeisler (Box 7)
  - Class of 1913
    - Adams-Hemingway (Box 9)
  - Class of 1914
    - Abbott-Moffett (Box 11)
    - Markle-Yule (Box 12)
  - Class of 1915
    - Adams-McNulty, F. (Box 13)
  - Class of 1916
    - Abromowitz-Polly (Box 15)
  - Class of 1917
    - Abeles-Foy (Box 16)
    - Freedman-Zetterstead (Box 17)
  - Class of 1918
    - Adams-Brace (Box 17)
    - Brainard-Simonds (Box 18)
    - Sinclair-Zenner (Box 19)
  - Class of 1919
    - Alpert-McMillian (Box 19)
    - McPartland-Young (Box 20)
  - Class of 1920
    - Adamson-Ramsay (Box 21)
    - Reker-Z (Box 22)
  - Class of 1921
    - A-Denny (Box 22)
    - DiBiase-Meyers (Box 23)
    - Netcher-Zizzete (Box 24)
  - Class of 1922 (Box 25)
  - Class of 1923
    - A-Cummings (Box 25)
    - Cushing-Shubs (Box 26)
    - Singer-Z (Box 27)
  - Class of 1924
    - A-Falk (Box 27)
    - Farnsworth-Stevens (Box 28)
    - Stickley-Zimmerman (Box 29)
  - Class of 1925
    - Abele-Knapp (Box 29)
    - Knipe-Ziegfeld (Box 30)
  - Class of 1926
    - Adams-Bognanoff (Box 30)
    - Bowie-Horowitz (Box 31)
    - Horton-Simkins (Box 32)
    - Smith-Young (Box 33)
  - Class of 1927
    - Allen-Derby (Box 33)
    - DeSaulles-Mansfield (Box 34)
    - Marsden-Yeager (Box 35)
  - Class of 1928
    - Abrashkin-Beach (Box 35)
    - Beardsley-Hord (Box 36)
    - House-Sturges (Box 37)
    - Swiertz-Zimmerman (Box 38)
  - Class of 1929
    - Fisher-Reeves (Box 39)
    - Reid-Zubritsky (Box 40)
  - Class of 1930
    - Abbott-Brown (Box 40)
    - Buckley-McGilmont (Box 41)
    - Maceachern-Yinkey (Box 42)
  - Class of 1931
    - Adams-Knopf (Box 43)
    - Knowles-White (Box 44)
    - Willard-Zalken (Box 45)
  - Class of 1932
    - Abbott-Kratz (Box 45)
    - Kushlan-Zsiga (Box 46)
  - Class of 1933
    - Engineering, Aholt-Ziurys (Box 47)
    - Sheffield
      - Adams-Garriques (Box 47)
      - Gasper-Young (Box 48)
  - Class of 1934
    - Alexander-Young, Engineering (Box 49)
    - Sheffield
      - Adams-Goldman (Box 49)
      - Gordon-Wright (Box 50)
  - Class of 1935
    - Engineering, Apple-Werner (Box 51)
    - Sheffield
      - Abbott-Hunt (Box 51)
      - Jackowski-Zabriski (Box 52)
  - Class of 1936
    - Engineering
      - McDonald-Williams (Box 53)
    - Sheffield
      - Ahlers-Meeker (Box 53)
      - Mestre-Woods (Box 54)
  - Class of 1937
    - Engineering, Alexander-Zimmerman (Box 54)
    - Sheffield
      - Adams-Scott (Box 55)
      - Scoville-Young (Box 56)
  - Class of 1938
    - Engineering, Abbe-Zweig (Box 56)
    - Sheffield
      - Abr-Dawson (Box 56)
      - Williams-Zemany (Box 58)
  - Class of 1939
    - Engineering, Adams-Wright (Box 58)
    - Sheffield
      - Aiken-Davis (Box 58)
      - Dawe-Underhill (Box 59)
      - Vulte-Z (Box 60)
  - Class of 1940
    - Engineering, Addoms-Zoabaum (Box 60)
    - Sheffield
      - Abrahams-Blending (Box 60)
      - Belakley-Dunklee (Box 61)
      - Orgelman-Wooste (Box 62)
  - Class of 1941
    - Engineering, Anderson-Wrieden (Box 62)
    - Sheffield
      - Allyn-Ballard (Box 62)
      - Beavers-Sanburn (Box 63)
      - Saunders-Zolot (Box 64)
- Student grade lists, 1931-1965; Accession 2004-A-102
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2041
  - 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 2)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - 1941 Fall (Box 3)
  - 1942 Jun (Box 3)
  - 1942 Sept (Box 3)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 3)
  - 1943 May (Box 3)
  - 1943 Oct (Box 3)
  - 1943 Fall (Box 3)
  - 1944 Jun (Box 3)
  - 1944 Oct. (Box 4)
  - 1945 Feb (Box 4)
  - 1945 Jun (Box 4)
  - 1945 Oct (Box 4)
  - 1946 Feb (Box 4)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 4)
  - 1947 Jun (Box 4)
  - 1948 Jan (Box 5)
  - 1948 Jun (Box 5)
  - 1949 Jan (Box 5)
  - 1949 Jun (Box 5)
  - 1949 Fall (Box 5)
  - 1950 Feb (Box 5)
  - 1950 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1951 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1951 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1952 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1952 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1955 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1955 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1956 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1956 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1957 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1957 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1958 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1958 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1959 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1959 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1960 Jan (Box 6)
  - 1960 Jun (Box 6)
  - 1961 Jan (Box 8)
  - 1961 Jun (Box 8)
  - 1962 Jan (Box 8)
  - 1962 Jun (Box 8)
  - 1963 Jan (Box 8)
  - 1963 Jun (Box 8)
  - 1963 Nov (Box 8)
  - 1964 Jan (Box 8)
  - 1964 Mar (Box 8)
  - 1964 Jun (Box 8)
  - 1964 Nov (Box 8)
  - 1965 Jan (Box 8)
  - 1965 Mar (Box 8)
  - 1965 Jun (Box 8)
- Sheffield Scientific School student transcripts, 1920-1950; Accession 2005-A-118
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2026
  - Nolte, Miles Herman Jr. (Box 3, Folder 4003)
  - Small, James Hampden 3rd (Box 3, Folder 5005)
- Conditions and warnings for the Class of 1915, Accession 2006-A-198
  The materials are open for research.
  - First term conditions, 1915 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Second term conditions, 1915 February (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Warnings, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Results of June exams, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Student grade lists, 1909; 1920-1921; Accession 2017-A-050
  - Grade lists, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grade lists, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)